NORMAN LO

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/norman-data-economist/

GitHub: https://github.com/NormanLo4319

Website: https://normanlo4319.github.io/Norman Lo Web/

Phone: (415) 706-8788 **Address:** San Francisco, CA 94107

E-mail: lokman@mail.sfsu.edu

SUMMARY

Data scientist with several years of experience in academic research and data analysis. Experienced in data management and statistical packages, such as Javascript, Python, R, Stata, MatLab, E-View, VBA, and SQL. Motivated to bring background in academic research and ability to build econometrics models with visualization to enhance decision-making and achieve company goals.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Javascript, Python, R, Stata, E-View, MatLab, SQL, noSQL, VBA

Data Manipulation & Visualization: pandas, matplotlib, seaborn, Tableau, Plotly, D3, ggplot2, scikits

Database: mySQL, postgeSQL, mongoDB, SQLAlchemy **Other:** Git, Flask, command line, machine learning, big data

PROJECTS

World Happiness Project

- Built a backend API with SQLAlchemy and Flask App for data request.
- Created frontend data product to request data from the API and provided visualizations for clients.
- Demonstrated the correlation between happiness and income inequality across 156 countries.

Public Health Scores & Yelp Customer-Based Rating

- Analyzed the restaurants' public health score and Yelp customer-based rating in San Francisco.
- Pulled and stored data from Yelp API and SFDPH on over 2000 restaurants into SQL database.

Food Environment & Health Outcomes

- Analyzed data from Yelp API and CDC public health for over 200 counties in the U.S.
- Generated statistical analysis and visualizations using Python Pandas and Matplotlib libraries.

EXPERIENCE

Adjunct Faculty, DVC, SFSU, USF, CCSF, Metro. State University	(2015 – present)
Student Equity Economics Advisor, City College of San Francisco	(2017 - 2018)
Native English ESL Teacher, South Korea	(2010 - 2013)
Merchandising Manager, First Global International Ltd, Hong Kong	(2007 - 2010)
Senior Merchandiser, Hallmark Cards Corp, Hong Kong	(2005 - 2007)

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: U.C. Berkeley Extension, San Francisco

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programing skills in Excel, VBA, Python, R, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data, and Machine Learning.

M.A. in Economics: San Francisco State University, San Francisco **B.A. in Economics:** San Francisco State University, San Francisco